## Dhavakumar AmarntharajanFeatured Resume

Web Developer seeking roles in Web Development, Web Designing, Application Programming, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Process Improvement having strong knowledge in Java 8, Spring Mvc, Hibernate, Restful, Javascript, jQuery, HTML, XML, C

Current Designation: Web Developer

Current Company: IVTL Infoview Technologies Private Limited

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Key Skills: Web Developer, Software Developer, Web Development, Web Designing, Application Programming, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Process Improvement, Java 8, Spring Mvc, Hibernate, HTML, XML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Jenkins

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 09e93b7a617e329a87Last Active: 9-Sep-20Last Modified: 9-Sep-20

Jump to SectionWork Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Passionate Developer with 4 years of experience in Web Development technologies and methodologies, seeking for an opportunity to associate myself with a leading organization that provides a challenging job to improve my innovative skills while making a significant contribution to the success of the company

Work Experience

IVTL Infoview Technologies Private Limited as Web Developer

Sep 2016 to Till Date

1 High Usability Enterprise (HUE) Jun 2018 - Present

ERP product - Works Application (Japan)

- \* Analyzing the catalog documents, functional business requirements and prepared Enterprise data relationship diagrams
- \* Designed and developed application with large user utility, involving recursive DB hits with high speed responses involving batch process using Apache Spark framework
- \* Responsible for integration of batch with front-end programs to deliver functional and cohesive codes to enhance the user experience
- \* Generated reports using Jaspersoft Studio

#2 Company V7 - QE AutoTest Nov 2017 - May 2018

**Testing Tool Development** 

- \* Preparing tool specification document for various components and created Automation test scripts for the specification
- \* Executed test scripts on different browsers/environments and fixed defects
- \* Facilitate specification enhancement and automation feasibility for new components

#3 CORTEX+ Sep 2016 - Oct 2017

Project management and issue tracking tool

Analyzing functional requirements and developed it in agile methodology

- \* Developed modules such as Leave Application, Issue List and Resource Allocation
- \* Worked in App generator module as well, responsible for updating java templates as per the new standards and enhancements
- \* Involved in timing analysis & critical load analysis and optimization based on the results

^ Back to Top

## Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from m.a.m college of engineering and technology in 2016

^ Back to Top

**IT Skills** 

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

Spring MVC, Hibernate 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Apache Spark (Basics), Selenide 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

TestNG, RESTful Web Services 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

JAVA 8, J2EE 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

HTML, XML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

JQUERY 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Oracle, Cassandra 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Apache Tomcat 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

GIT, Jenkins, SonarQube 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Eclipse Luna 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

C, C++ 2016 0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

WINDOWS, UNIX 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language Proficiency Read Write Speak

**English Expert** 

Tamil Expert